[{"id": "6015ef03fe83fe1f2a824c0c", "question": "In what year did Christmas become a federal holiday in the United States?", "answer": "1870", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c183", "question": "What food item literally means \"twice-cooked\"?", "answer": "Biscuit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f3", "question": "In The Simpsons, who do Jumbo and Kearney usually hang around with?", "answer": "Dolph", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab952086faa38a764be512", "question": "What was the first production car to break the 200 mph top speed limit?", "answer": "The Ferrari F40", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9b", "question": "What movie did the villain Harry Powell appear in?", "answer": "The Night of the Hunter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb44", "question": "At what university did Tiger Woods play collegiate golf for two years before turning pro?", "answer": "Stanford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05b", "question": "What is the name of Amy Winehouse's first album?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339130", "question": "Britomart, Duessa, and Archimago are characters in which incomplete epic poem?", "answer": "The Faerie Queene", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b6", "question": "What company produced the \"Brownie\" camera?", "answer": "Kodak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36ce40ada16518afdc03e", "question": "What car company makes the Econoline van", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b512", "question": "What is the other name for the card game Patience?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede34d6ce05a3942286dd1", "question": "Who was originally cast as Holly Golightly in \"Breakfast at Tiffany\u2019s\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e3", "question": "What city is the capital of New York State?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7137a9e54d890926f6dc", "question": "Where is the world's first underwater restaurant?", "answer": "Maldives -- The Conrad Maldives Rangali Island hotel is home to Ithaa Undersea Restaurant, which opened in 2005.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ca3c8344f0f6af5b066632", "question": "What is the fear of frogs called?", "answer": "Ranidaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049e7ecf93664eb10486b4", "question": "What country does the rock band \"Enter Shikari\" originate from?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede0b96ce05a3942286dba", "question": "Which Bavarian castle did Walt Disney sculpt Cinderella's after?", "answer": "Neuschwanstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597743a3284458f1d785442a", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d7", "question": "What is the capital of Hawaii?", "answer": "Honolulu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf06", "question": "What is the study of bells called?", "answer": "Campanologist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ed", "question": "How many vehicles did the original \"Gran Turismo\" video game have?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7b", "question": "In Nathaniel Hawthorne's \"The Scarlet Letter\", what was the letter and what did it stand for?", "answer": "A for adultry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339569", "question": "Which rock music icon plays Jack 'Strafer' Celliers in, Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b840", "question": "In which sport would you be judged on your pike or your jack knife?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22d", "question": "What country are eclairs said to have originated from?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fcc1b2dc97eb73f6a51a270", "question": "According to mythology, who gifted olives to the Greeks?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fd", "question": "Who was the only bare-footed Beatle on the Abbey Road album cover?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30c", "question": "Who played the role of Marcy Runkle on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Pamela Adlon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eea6fe83fe1f2a824c09", "question": "What is eaten traditionally in the UK the day before Ash Wednesday?", "answer": "Pancakes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80351de59ea584496fe9c", "question": "Dodie Smith wrote what book that later became a very popular Disney film?", "answer": "The Hundred and One Dalmatians", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba4d8874c93a3298b2149", "question": "What is the Welsh name for Mount Snowdon?", "answer": "Yr Wyddfa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee6", "question": "What two colors make the color green?", "answer": "Blue and yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b605", "question": "Which impressionist featured his wife Camille, in \"The Woman in the Green Dress\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c104", "question": "Carbonade Flamande is a dish made with what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067a6eff9c0647b50a8059", "question": "In 2016, which vessel became the first solar-powered aircraft to circumnavigate the Earth?", "answer": "Solar Impulse 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589e25db0d66a186cb54f", "question": "French fries are claimed to have originated in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b279", "question": "What political party was led until 1985 by the brutal Pol Pot?", "answer": "The Khmer Rouge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c237", "question": "What are the two traditional colors of Halloween?", "answer": "Orange and black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c703", "question": "What famous 19th-century American writer was issued a patent for adjustable elastic suspenders?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f732ca9e54d890926f6ef", "question": "The ancient Egyptian symbol \"Ouroboros\" depicts a serpent eating what?", "answer": "Its own tail", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c24", "question": "Who wrote \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "Francis Scott Key", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdfbe8e003d27d341092bd0", "question": "Why are Amsterdam's buildings so narrow?", "answer": "A tax loophole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdabc2c0b8cce1e6fda705c", "question": "A pentagram's four lower points symbolize air, fire, water and which other item?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f164ce1f9b80650dbe7f930", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Robinson Crusoe\"?", "answer": "Daniel Defoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e63afe83fe1f2a824bc9", "question": "Who ultimately succeeded King Alfred the Great as \"King of the Anglo-Saxons\"?", "answer": "Edward the Elder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c400", "question": "The insect known as the yellow jacket is a type of what?", "answer": "Wasp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fc", "question": "What is missing from a navel orange?", "answer": "Seeds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b84ce662d71a53651021", "question": "Which Christmas song was originally written for a Broadway musical?", "answer": "\"White Christmas\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb5f37e83c707845b2123", "question": "Scientists believe human fingers get wrinkly when wet for what reason?", "answer": "To better grip objects while wet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bdef877e98cb9777895b", "question": "What mountain is nicknamed the \"Savage Mountain\"?", "answer": "K-2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea473dff048f679a45abab", "question": "What kind of mountains are the Himalayas?", "answer": "Young Fold mountains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b350", "question": "Who was the first person to break the sound barrier?", "answer": "Chuck Yeager", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c7e1fbde8045e48466c9", "question": "How many stomachs does a llama have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e52", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Old Yeller\"?", "answer": "Chuck Connors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc9", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional band \"Drive Shaft\"?", "answer": "Lost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067bb3ff9c0647b50a8067", "question": "What video game console did Microsoft release in August, 2016?", "answer": "Xbox One S", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2fa958d116dab4aecb4c", "question": "What past carmaker's ads used the slogan \"We Build Excitement\"?", "answer": "Pontiac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0c", "question": "What historical event provides the backdrop for the 1905 novel \"The Scarlet Pimpernel\"?", "answer": "The French Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917a", "question": "Which Philip K. Dick novelette is the movie \"Total Recall\" based on?", "answer": "We Can Remember It For You Wholesale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339510", "question": "Who played Molly's love interest in the movie \"Pretty in Pink\"?", "answer": "Andrew McCarthy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff3", "question": "Which novel by Louis de Bernieres is set in Cephalonia?", "answer": "Captain Corelli's Mandolin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ebb408d98002fdd633b1", "question": "When was the maiden voyage of the \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940e", "question": "The 1997 movie \"Dante's Peak\" tells the story of a town that is threatened by what?", "answer": "A volcano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a074", "question": "What song won the grammy for \"song of the year\" in 1977?", "answer": "You Light Up My Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36f", "question": "What do the British call gasoline?", "answer": "Petrol", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fe", "question": "The flowers of the curry tree are what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc8a06de0eb824d4052fd", "question": "\"The Blue House\" is the official residence of the leader of what country?", "answer": "South Korea -- Originally known as \"Gyeongmudae\", the name was changed in 1960 to \"Cheong Wa Dae\", meaning blue house.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4aa", "question": "Which desert covers part of China and Mongolia?", "answer": "Gobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa52", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritania?", "answer": "Nouakchott", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339736", "question": "In the TV series \"Lost\", which airline's plane crashed?", "answer": "Oceanic Airlines", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6652da5bfecdd737e085c", "question": "What was the U.S. population in 1900?", "answer": "76,094,000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfbcb1003d27d341092bc7", "question": "How many countries did Yugoslavia split into?", "answer": "Five", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ee", "question": "Who played the role of Daniel in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Ralph Macchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b9", "question": "Texas City is located at the mouth of what bay?", "answer": "Galveston Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a80", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a temperature of how many degrees?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1eca1145fb29466707387", "question": "What does the Qantas airline name stand for?", "answer": "Queensland and Northern Territory Aerial Services", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b413", "question": "In what year was nylon first synthesized?", "answer": "1935", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b885364247bf200fb881", "question": "The Easter lily is a native plant of which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdd", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured David Bowie and Rip Torn?", "answer": "The Man Who Fell to Earth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ec", "question": "Which US state is home to the city of Cape Girardeau?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad1", "question": "What book is divided into 114 chapters called \"suras\"?", "answer": "The Qur'an", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358d9f5db0d66a186cb562", "question": "Pat Sullivan is often credited with creating which cartoon character?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da5", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Being There\"?", "answer": "Jack Warden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed3", "question": "Of what nationality was explorer Captain James Cook?", "answer": "British", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339581", "question": "Which actress-turned-diplomat won a special Oscar for \"outstanding contribution to screen entertainment\" in 1934?", "answer": "Shirley Temple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985a", "question": "In the movie \"Princess Mononoke\", the Forest Spirit most resembles what animal?", "answer": "A Stag", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c848877e98cb977789e1", "question": "Which country has hosted the Wife Carrying World Championships since the competition\u2019s founding in 1992?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d7b3745b36be73039d8", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3c", "question": "What chain did Ray Kroc build?", "answer": "McDonald's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f2066682715b82711ce6", "question": "Feijoada is the national dish of which South American country?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c278", "question": "What is November's birthstone?", "answer": "Topaz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c173", "question": "What is a clarsach?", "answer": "A Gaelic Harp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339441", "question": "Where does the platoon in the movie \"Full Metal Jacket\" attend boot camp?", "answer": "Parris Island", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d117d64fea7fe947a2227e", "question": "Which German firm produced the World War II plane known as the Condor?", "answer": "Focke-Wulf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3b57c73aa70ea0b70ae8", "question": "Where was the first European settlement in Australia located?", "answer": "Port Jackson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf17", "question": "At which sport was Fred Perry crowned world champion in 1929?", "answer": "Table Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74d", "question": "Which US state is home to the Catskill Mountains?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6f", "question": "Who played Willy Wonka in the original version of \"Willy Wonka and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339089", "question": "Who beheaded Medusa?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ea", "question": "How much money do you start a game of standard \"Monopoly\" with?", "answer": "$1500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c15", "question": "Who are the four main characters of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Stan, Kyle, Cartman and Kenny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada6", "question": "The \"Italian Plague of 1629-31\" is also referred to as by what other name?", "answer": "Great Plague of Milan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7344eeec85e375820b232", "question": "Who was the only US president to not marry?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce6", "question": "What Victor Hugo title character was enamored with a poor gypsy girl named Esmerelda?", "answer": "Quasimodo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea1", "question": "What was frontierswoman Martha Burke better known as?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948e", "question": "Who directed the 1993 movie \"Nightmare Before Christmas\"?", "answer": "Henry Selick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c123", "question": "What is the Binot-Simon Scale used to measure?", "answer": "Intelligence", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a001", "question": "What British TV series featured Tinky Winky, Dipsy, Laa-Laa, and Po?", "answer": "Teletubbies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f45cfaf848b908361b874", "question": "What cake is also known as a \"Domino cake\"?", "answer": "Battenberg cake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5d", "question": "What shortage killed over one million Irish people in the 1840s?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed4", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339042", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Naked and the Dead\"?", "answer": "Norman Mailer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd8d1e347d002c297e4c9", "question": "In Greek mythology, whose father created the Labyrinth?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba99", "question": "Where did former NFL star Joe Montana play college football?", "answer": "Notre Dame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ec0e08d98002fdd633b6", "question": "Which singer wrote the autobiography \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e7f8b24f84e0b9f9ffc1", "question": "What is the capital of Australia's Western Australia state?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa3df6ce05a3942286eac", "question": "Which Oscar-winner studied opera as a teen?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe9", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef0", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Willy Loman?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928b", "question": "\"Highlander\" tells the story of which immortal swords-man?", "answer": "Connor MacLeod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339438", "question": "During WWII what material were the Oscars made of to conserve metal for the war effort?", "answer": "Plaster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3631815febcc896f9265", "question": "Which actor took the male lead in Hitchcock's film \"The Birds\"?", "answer": "Rod Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Selma's Choice,\" Homer can't go to Duff Gardens because he's sick from eating what?", "answer": "An old, old sandwich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac7", "question": "What sport is the subject of the book \"Sands of Time\"?", "answer": "Beach volleyball", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe771d1eec85e375820b300", "question": "Which country hosts the world's highest marathon?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc28d6de0eb824d4052e6", "question": "What is the nickname for the island of Trinidad?", "answer": "Land of the Hummingbird", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a066cad1ec93f27df76a", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ea", "question": "What is by far the most famous New York-based piece of work by French sculptor Auguste Bartholdi?", "answer": "The Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae9431574a5ce6b56b8244", "question": "What job did Agatha Christie's second husband do?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b92", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Monkees\" were made?", "answer": "58", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29e", "question": "Who was the male lead in the 1955 film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b0", "question": "What is the name of the coffee shop the \"Friends\" gang frequents?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77a", "question": "What city serves as the capital of Northern Ireland?", "answer": "Belfast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe656adae7e414034b5aecf", "question": "Which King of England was faced with the Peasants' Revolt in 1381?", "answer": "Richard II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af98", "question": "In which war was the Battle of Ramillies?", "answer": "War of Spanish Succession", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f2", "question": "Who sang the title song for the 1978 suspense film \"Eyes of Laura Mars\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f90", "question": "Which character is the narrator of Melville's \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c89d9d011619dd6d415487", "question": "What is the name of the giant Canadian in South Park?", "answer": "Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ad", "question": "How many wings does a butterfly have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eec", "question": "El Greco painted a famous View of what Spanish city?", "answer": "Toledo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be37", "question": "How many players are there in a standard soccer team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af258dfb63e5727cf5a4849", "question": "Who sang the 1995 song \"Boom Boom Boom\"?", "answer": "The Outhere Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59c1cd8c7bd84c0ea43ad429", "question": "Skopje is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Macedonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05f", "question": "What famous Cherokee Indian created the alphabet for the Cherokee language?", "answer": "Sequoyah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600243e54be4723ccac2219d", "question": "\"Leaves of Grass\", first published in 1855, is a poetry collection by which American poet?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85e", "question": "What does a hygrometer measure?", "answer": "Humidity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049938cf93664eb104868e", "question": "What Charles Dickens work features the character of Mr. Wardle?", "answer": "The Pickwick Papers", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4e", "question": "The 1999 Russell Crowe film \"The Insider\" concerned a whistle-blower in what industry?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc56", "question": "The necktie dates back to what century?", "answer": "17th", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbe136ce05a3942286ee7", "question": "What film has the quote, \"What we've got here is...failure to communicate\"?", "answer": "Cool Hand Luke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab13f6baab681b09292170", "question": "What car manufacturer was the first to mass-produce and equip a production vehicle with a V4 engine?", "answer": "Lancia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939a", "question": "How many Oscar nominations did the 1995 movie \"Apollo 13\" receive?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ef", "question": "In The Simpsons, which immigrant in Springfield actually got deported once?", "answer": "Groundskeeper Willie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbe", "question": "Which war was fought along the 38th parallel?", "answer": "The Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedd9e06ce05a3942286d7d", "question": "What was the first movie to be rated PG-13?", "answer": "\"Red Dawn\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f8", "question": "In the movie \"Pulp Fiction\", what is the name of the restaurant Mia brings Vincent to?", "answer": "Jack-Rabbit Slim's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef622d6ce05a3942286e5c", "question": "What boy band did Justin Timberlake belong to?", "answer": "NSYNC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb83", "question": "What citrus beverage has used the ad slogan \"Open a Bottle of Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Sunny Delight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891a", "question": "What Italian city was Michelangelo raised in?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b17448fbb2d29f81593b6fb", "question": "Nat King Cole died in which year?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a3c839a039f3d7859290ffa", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", who portrayed the blacksmith, Quint Asper?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecc", "question": "What baseball player is Santiago's hero in \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Joe DiMaggio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb26", "question": "What is the common name for coagulated soy milk curd pressed into blocks?", "answer": "Tofu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b067", "question": "Which Space Shuttle broke apart during re-entry in February, 2003?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e5f0fc7d274615ecf514536", "question": "Which plant has the most genes of any living plant or animal?", "answer": "Paris Japonica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded1deea2747c8aff16d37", "question": "Which musical do the songs \"Look at Me I'm Sandra Dee\" and \"Beauty School Dropout\" come from?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d119564fea7fe947a2228d", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95a97e55722f97b22684d0", "question": "What short film featured Mickey Mouse\u2019s first appearance?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe699e120565ad31a57c74d", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c029", "question": "What sport is sometimes called rugger?", "answer": "Rugby union", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4af", "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f84", "question": "What is the name of the son of the witch Sycorax?", "answer": "Caliban in The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab5370b8cce1e6fda704b", "question": "How can you tell if cranberries are ripe?", "answer": "They bounce like rubber balls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69c1e20565ad31a57c767", "question": "Who founded the world's first secular nursing school?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fc38fe83fe1f2a824c3e", "question": "Where was the very first Hard Rock Cafe opened?", "answer": "The first Hard Rock Cafe opened on June 14, 1971 at Gloucester House, Piccadilly, London.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c766877e98cb977789cd", "question": "Where is Bohemian Switzerland National Park?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc15aec223966ae8f8869", "question": "Which country music star sang about \"Drinkin' My Baby Goodbye?\"", "answer": "Charlie Daniels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ede", "question": "What position was first held by Kenesaw Mountain Landis?", "answer": "US Baseball commissioner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c3", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Krusty Gets Busted\", according to Bart, what do all good-hearted people have?", "answer": "Small feet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7464a9e54d890926f6f6", "question": "How many steps must visitors take to reach the site of two Buddhist temples in China called Fanjingshan?", "answer": "8,888", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d8", "question": "What element combines with sodium to make ordinary table salt?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a94bc61d1b4d384d5d671", "question": "Who is Dana Elaine Owens more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339126", "question": "\"Samson and Delilah\" is an opera by which French composer?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Saens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3ca8c73aa70ea0b70aed", "question": "In what year did Washington, D.C become the capital of the U.S.?", "answer": "1800", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3f2", "question": "What is the fear of cosmic phenomenon known as?", "answer": "Kosmikophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339729", "question": "Which musical instrument was Buddy Rich best known for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392bd", "question": "What 1960s-1970s folk singer had relationships with both Bob Dylan and Steve Jobs?", "answer": "Joan Baez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0c", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in Soy Sauce, besides water?", "answer": "Wheat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f92", "question": "In what modified vegetable did Cinderella travel to the ball in?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7d504877e98cb97778a63", "question": "Who won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1918 for the services he rendered to the advancement of physics by his discovery of energy quanta?", "answer": "Max Planck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c816", "question": "What grape is called Primitivo in Europe?", "answer": "Zinfandel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4df", "question": "What fruit comes in Damson and Mirabelle variety?", "answer": "Plums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b16", "question": "What actor did Melanie Griffith marry, and divorce, twice?", "answer": "Don Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b50906d333868d34d6e4", "question": "What kind of flower was Jesus talking about when he said \"They toil not, neither do they spin\"?", "answer": "Lilies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30d", "question": "Who played the role of Charlie Runkle on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Evan Handler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c731", "question": "How many sides does a heptagon have?", "answer": "7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cd", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Unconditional Surrender\"?", "answer": "Ulysses S. Grant", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1f", "question": "What author created Discworld?", "answer": "Terry Pratchett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339720", "question": "How old is Buffy in the first TV season of \"Buffy The Vampire Slayer\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990b", "question": "What TV show character lived at 129 West 81st St, Apt. 5A in New York City?", "answer": "Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f2", "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the 1942 film, \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Thumper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c1", "question": "In The Simpsons, which character died by getting hit with T-shirts?", "answer": "Maude", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97c", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Storting?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac2", "question": "What, partially acapella song, did the Eagles have a Top 40 hit with in 1981?", "answer": "Seven Bridges Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b9", "question": "What is a calorie a unit of?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aef", "question": "What is a \"dhampir\"?", "answer": "A half human, half vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c834", "question": "Seafloor spreading at midoceanic ridges is how scientists first discovered the periodic reversal of what?", "answer": "The earth's magnetic field", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf05", "question": "What large red flower is the floral emblem of New South Wales?", "answer": "Waratah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae67", "question": "What nationality was Christopher Columbus?", "answer": "Italian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f4e8ff048f679a45aacd", "question": "Megalophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Large things or objects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc8420078d18506ae1fe489", "question": "What species is the tallest tree in the world?", "answer": "California Redwood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7ffb133a3a814d89068c61", "question": "The US made \"Medium Tank, M4\" is better known as what?", "answer": "The Sherman tank", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64e", "question": "What must a mole do every four hours so it doesn't die?", "answer": "Eat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae936c574a5ce6b56b823b", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339368", "question": "In the 1960 movie \"Psycho\", what actor plays the private detective?", "answer": "Martin Balsam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb03f65ff7d326b622a61", "question": "The Atlas Mountains stretch through which countries?", "answer": "Morocco, Algeria and Tunisia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe12e58e39efa6330e0fed2", "question": "Which US state has the most lighthouses?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb1c06af497e33de805791c", "question": "What baseball announcer was famous for this signature phrase: \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a793", "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is considered to be part of which geographical region?", "answer": "Caribbean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d2", "question": "In \"Texas Hold 'Em\", what is the name of the fourth community card dealt?", "answer": "The turn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e5", "question": "What nationality was writer Arthur C. Clarke?", "answer": "British", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067ecaff9c0647b50a807e", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea489bff048f679a45abb1", "question": "If you throw a ball in the air, what curve does it trace out?", "answer": "Parabola", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e804ffde59ea584496fea8", "question": "Archie Moore is typically associated with which sport?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b4", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Andorra and Portugal?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c2", "question": "What is Marilyn Monroe's real name?", "answer": "Norma Jeane Mortenson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f146cee580c7f8fd1e4e", "question": "Who said, \"Well done is better than well said.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d51", "question": "Author Margaret Atwood is a graduate of which Canadian University?", "answer": "University of Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a183", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\", who drove the Boulder Mobile?", "answer": "The Slag Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a64e", "question": "What is the Napa Valley best known for?", "answer": "Wine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339057", "question": "Who wrote the \"Aeneid\"?", "answer": "Virgil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008ca4cf842fa4c4ba96a0", "question": "What is Jimmy Carter's middle name?", "answer": "Earl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty the Clown's helper monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8af", "question": "In what city would you find Centennial Olympic Park?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a13", "question": "What was Ralph Kramden's weekly salary as a bus driver on \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "$62", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339207", "question": "What Scottish city is the setting for \"Trainspotting\" according to the plot?", "answer": "Edinburgh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339516", "question": "What was the name of Jasmine's tiger in Disney's \"Aladdin\"?", "answer": "Rajah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bdc", "question": "In which city is A Midsummer Nights Dream set?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ae", "question": "What do x and y chromosomes combine in making?", "answer": "Males", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4bf", "question": "Who was assassinated by her own bodyguards in 1984?", "answer": "Indira Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e4", "question": "What was Higgins first name in the TV show \"Magnum PI\"?", "answer": "Jonathan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339810", "question": "What was rapper Rick Ross' occupation prior to becoming a hip hop artist?", "answer": "Correctional officer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af7", "question": "Which character killed Captain Ahab?", "answer": "Moby-Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be7", "question": "Who are the creators of the TV show \"Seinfeld\"?", "answer": "Larry David and Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc36", "question": "What basketball superstar is nicknamed \"His Airness\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e23", "question": "Who's the most famous resident of Mr. Peebles' pet shop?", "answer": "Magilla Gorilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067f79ff9c0647b50a8085", "question": "On what date did the 2016 Dyn Cyberattack take place, rendering some of the largest Internet services unusable for several hours?", "answer": "October 21, 2016", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeeb", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934a", "question": "\"Tabitha\" was a spin-off of what popular TV show?", "answer": "Bewitched", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339646", "question": "Which of the four Beatles was the eldest?", "answer": "Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b5", "question": "The Golden Gate Bridge is located in what city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}]